[Music] cassandra a wide column store nosql
[音乐]cassandra 一个广泛的列存储 nosql
database famous for its ability to distribute petabytes of data with
数据库，以其以
unmatched reliability and performance it was created in 2008 by avinash lakshman
无与伦比的可靠性和性能分发 PB 级数据的能力而闻名。它于 2008
who was responsible for scaling facebook's inbox search feature by 2010
年由负责扩展facebook 收件箱搜索功能的 avinash lakshman 创建于 2010 年
it became a top-level apache project and today is used at scale by big companies
它成为顶级 apache 项目和今天被苹果等大公司大规模使用，
like apple which manages a staggering 100 petabytes of data across hundreds of
它管理着数
thousands of server instances it's a general purpose database with use cases
十万个服务器实例中惊人的 100 PB 数据，它是一个通用数据库，包含
for e-commerce content management audit logging and everything in between each
电子商务内容管理审计日志的用例以及每个实例之间的所有
instance of cassandra is called a node and typically stores about two terabytes
内容 cassandra 被称为节点，通常存储大约 2 TB
of data what makes it special though is that nodes can be easily distributed to
的数据，但它的特别之处在于节点可以轻松分布以
scale horizontally every node has the same read write capabilities of another
水平扩展每个节点都具有与另一个节点相同的读写能力，
node but is responsible for its own partition of data nodes are grouped
但负责自己的数据分区节点是
together in a cluster or ring and data is typically replicated on multiple
在集群或环中组合在一起，数据通常在多个节点上复制
nodes which means no single point of failure and 100 uptime the data is
w 这意味着没有单点故障和 100 次正常运行时间数据被
wrapped in a key space giving developers control over how it replicates in the
包装在一个键空间中，使开发人员可以控制它如何在
cluster each key space contains one or more tables which represent tabular data
集群中复制每个键空间包含一个或多个表，这些表代表
like you might find in a relational database however it's schema-less and
您可能在关系数据库中找到的表格数据，但是它是 无模式并且
can handle unstructured data which developers can manage with the cassandra
可以处理开发人员可以使用 cassandra
query language the easiest way to get started is by creating a free serverless
查询语言管理的非结构化数据 最简单的入门方法是使用 astra 创建一个免费的无服务器
database with astra it deploys to the cloud of your choice then scales
数据库，然后将其部署到您选择的云中，然后
automatically on demand first we'll need to define a key space which acts as a
首先根据需要自动扩展要定义一个充当复制容器的密钥空间，
container for replication next we'll need to connect to the database which
接下来我们需要连接到数据库，这
can be accomplished in a variety of ways it has sdks for major languages and a
可以通过多种方式完成，它具有用于主要语言的 sdks 和一个
tool called stargate that makes data accessible via ras graphql and grpc or
名为 stargate 的工具，该工具可以通过 ras graphql 访问数据和 grpc 或者
you can execute raw cql code which is a subset of sql create a table and include
您可以执行作为 sql 子集的原始 cql 代码创建一个表并包含
a primary key to uniquely identify every row then each column will have its own
一个主键来唯一标识每一行然后每一列 将有自己的
name and data type now add data to that table with the insert into statement
名称和数据类型现在使用 insert into 语句将数据添加到该表
then you select to read data from the table it's also possible to use the
然后您选择从表中读取数据也可以使用
where clause to filter and query the data but an index will be required on
where 子句过滤和查询数据，但需要索引
the column on the surface this may look a lot like a relational database but it
从表面上看，这可能看起来很像一个关系数据库，但它
doesn't support joins and that's by design instead of modeling data into
不支持连接，这是设计使然，而不是将数据建模到
small normalized tables in cassandra it's denormalized to match the structure
cassandra 中的小型规范化表中，它是非规范化的，以匹配
of known queries making reads much faster at scale and it's also possible
已知查询的结构，从而使大规模读取速度更快，并且 也
to implement storage attached indexing to handle complex relational queries
可以实现存储附加索引来处理复杂的关系查询
this has been cassandra in 100 seconds let me know if you want to see a full
这已经 cassandra 在 100 秒内让我知道如果你想在评论中看到完整的
tutorial in the comments thanks for watching and i will see you in the next
教程 感谢观看，我会在下
one
一个